SUBHAM SWAIN FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

+91 7008819985 | <u>subhamswain00@gmail.com ||https://www.linkedin.com/in/subhswai/</u>|https://github.com/subhamswain

OBJECTIVE

A Software developer with 2.5 years of experience in maintaining and building webpages and helping companiescreate and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of continuous learning from senior developers.. Having experience in HTML, CSS, javascript, React js, Redux, Nodejs, AWS,

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Anand Rathi Wealth Pvt Ltd(Fintech)

Jan 2024 – Present

Full Stack Developer

Project - WorkStation(Postgresql,Python,Flask,SQL Alchemy,React Js,Redux,AWS EC2,S3,API GATEWAY,Lambda)

Description - WorkStation is a product where it shows the information of client about equity, brokerage, mutual fund details

- Improved API performance by fine-tuning Postregsql queries and SqlAlchemy ORM using Flask
- Integrated third-party Accord Api.
- Worked on the integration of backend and frontend and deployment using AWS and used AWS S3,EC2,Lambda.
- Utilized Axios to access API information for complex features on UI, in frontend using React Js

Innefu labs Pvt ltd(MGS Technologies)

Aug 2022 – Oct 2023

Python Programmer

Project - Department of Justice(Postgresql,Django,Python,React js,Redux,AWS)

Description -Department of Justice is a interview panel member system where there are 2 login the system one is panel member and other is for applicant.

- Worked with api integration using frontend and backend using React js and Django.
- Developed using panel member and other is for applicant where applicant can choose apply multiple interview category.

Target Integration - Noida

Feb 2022 – Aug 2022

Software Engineer

Project -Flamingo Rat. (Python, Flask, Mysql, Pandas, Numpy, Javascript)

Description-Flamingo Rat is an encryption and decryption system, so 2 windows one is for the client and another is for the server

- Created encryption and Decryption for client and server where client can send encrypted message, file to the server.
- Developed api thirty party intergation using JWT authentication.

IWCN - Remote

Aug 2021 – Feb 2021

Application Developer(Python,Postgresql,Django,Javascript,Html,CSS)

Project -Exfi(Postgresql,Django,Python,React js,Redux,AWS)

Description -Exfi streamlines business transactions with comprehensive billing software, generating accurate invoices, building quotations, tracking inventory, and more—all in one compact tool with more than 100+ features.

- A website's admin panel for efficient user management, enabling user addition, and streamlined application control.
- Assign customized Django permissions as per User Role.

EDUCATION

Biju Pattnaik University of Technology - Rourkela, Odisha

2019

B Tech: Computer Science, 6.9 CGPA

SKILLS & OTHERS

Programming Languages: Python | Java Script

Frameworks & Library: Django | Flask | Fast API | Node.js | React.js

Data Base: PostgreSQL | MongoDB | MySql

Cloud& Others: AWS S3,EC2,API Gateway,Lambda |CI/CD pipelines |Docker | Git | GitHub|Bitbucket

Ticketing Tools:Jira